Guide to the Robert J. Zehnder papers,
Zehnder, Robert J papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert J. Zehnder papers,
6763
Robert J. Zehnder
4 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Research Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, grape vouchers, and notes.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Robert Zehnder was an amateur viticulturist in Summerville, South Carolina who specialized in breeding "southern" grapes.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, grape vouchers, card file, research, and notes.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Zehnder, Robert J.
Subjects:
Viticulture.; Grapes.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Also see The Liberty Hyde Bailey Hortorium for grape hybrid vouchers, grape leaf pressings and notes from this collection.
Accession folder has photos of Zehnder, his grapes, and his vineyard. Some photos are on CD-ROM, also two video interview clips.
Forms part of the Eastern Wine and Grape Archive. (EWGA)
CONTAINER LIST
- J. Gavin Applleby, 1979-1980, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Hoyt Adair, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- A.J. Bullard, 1987, Jan. 1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- B.J. Bull, July, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Dr. H.C. Barrett, 1973, 1986-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Herbert Barrett, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Jeff Bloodworth, 1983-1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Dr. David W. Cain, May-June, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Lee Sharp - Citrus, Dec 20, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Lee Sharp, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Lon J. Rombough- 1900's USDA, Dec 13, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Lester H. Davis, 1990-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Notes - Dunstans Vineyard, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Dunstans OIV article and Translation, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- DRX 61-6, July 29, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- DRX 67-4, May 27, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Dunstan Rotundi Hybrids DRX 68-19 Tet, May 5, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- DRX-Dunstan 70-13, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- DRX 72-26, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- DRX 73-26, April 23, 1995, April 30, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Dunstans Publications, 1962-1963, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- D340, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Dustans Early Hybrids, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Deoring, 1990, 1999, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Aurelia Dunstan Wallace, 2001-2005 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Dunstan Wallace, 1987-1998 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Florida Numbers, 1989, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Dr. John Mortensen, 1967, 1971-1980, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Joseph L. Fennell, 1958-1965, June 24, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Joseph L. Fennell, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Joseph Fennell Part II, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Fennells 3way Hybrid, May 23, 1995, June 12-17, 2004, May 30, 1998, May 23, 1995, 1995-2004 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- CB9-23, April 30, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Flo AA 12-3, 1993-1997, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Ferrer Seedlings, 1963-1964, 1986, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Ferrer Seedlings, 1961, Sept 6, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- B.O. Fry, 1962-1968, 1981, April 4, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Pione Golet, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Bob and Sandra Gamble, March 16, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Ga 1-6-1 or 31-16-1 or 31-6-1 Higgins X F30 Seedling, July 12, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- S.C. Henson-Chesnee, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- W.L. Hagerman, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- C.P. 'Pat' Hegwood, 1964, 1993, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- James Harris, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- David Johnson, 1999-2005 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- David Johnson, 1992, 1996, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- John Kreutziger, 1990-1995 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Kowalski, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Larry Little, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- T. Votney Munson, 1978, 1988, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Dr. John McGrew, May 1984, June 1984 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Jack E. McCoy - Kaki Test Group Grifton N.C., 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Michael McConkey, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Glen Melcher, Jan, 1993, Dec 2, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Keith Moon, October 9, 1988, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 55)
- William E. Minnis, 1983-1984, Jan 26, 2005, Dec 16, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- William C. Olien, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Palms, April 16, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Jim Plymel, Feb, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Rice, May, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Rotundifolias, Sept 11, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Marvin "Trey" Lewis, Sept 28, 1997, April 1, 1998, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- L. Reep, 1989-1995, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Reep's Photo 82.3.1, July 29, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Ramming, 1999, 2003-2005 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Clivi Simms, 1988, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Elmer Swenson, Dec 12, 1992, May 10, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Trace Element Deficiency, 1986, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Vitis Specimens, June 1, 1962, Sept 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Frank A. Watlington, 1965-1969, April 22, 1973, 1977, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Martin Waterman, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Dr. Wylie-Chester, 1961, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Yarnell Collection, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Pierces Disease Color Photos, Nov-Dec 1987, Jan-Feb 1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Southern Home, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- J.S. Akin "Sherwood", 1997-1999, 1988-1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Southeast Nurseries, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Dan Berry, Feb 9, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Cliff Ambers, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Joseph W. McRoe, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Total Solids, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Pistillate Vines, March, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Ph Agri, Jan 22, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Plant Locations, April 1, 1994, 1999, March 24, 2004, August, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- French Hybrids, 1950-1952 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Anthony Fischinger, June 1999 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Photo Reproductions, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Color Copies, 1962-1974 (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Luke Clark, March 3, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Dave Griffin, Dec, 2005, Feb, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Grape Breeders, 2000, 1981-1984, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- 1980 Symposium (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Don Kelsey, March 1, 2004, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Daniel R. Berry, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Reep - Lewis, July 5, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Stark, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Cornell-Geruva, cousins, 1999-2006 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Gregor Mendel, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Paul H. Zmoda, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- 1987 Seed Crop Copy, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Seed Production, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Breeding Records, 2000-2003 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Breeding Records, Number Assignments, 1961-1998 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- USDA, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- David Ramming, 1996-2003 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Robert Louis Farrer, Feb, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Don Slinger, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Citrus etc., 1991-1995, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Dr. Katie Rigert, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- David Griffin, Dec 19, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Euvitis-Rotundifolia Hybrids, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Vitis, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Pirovano, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- "gold", 1997-1999, June 20, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Misc Zehnder Related Materials, 2005-2007 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Selected Clones in Zehnder's Vineyard (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Color Photos, 1970's-1980's (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Color Seedlings, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Cveighton Gupton, 1989, 1997-2000 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Cooking-Measurements, Substitutions, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Carolina Bays, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Earth Measurement, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Christian Crusade, 1981, 1990, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Attilio Scienza, 1985, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- William Minnis, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- William H. Collins, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Bob Gamble, June 1997 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Montmorenei Vineyards, 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Dr. Ronald Lane, 1973, 1988, 1991, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Dr. H.P. Olmo, 1954-1955, 1964-1970, 1996, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- New Enitis, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Correspondence: Cain, Ramming, Tarailo, 1979, 1988-1989, 1993, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Pierces Disease, 1997-2001 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Z67-7-5 (3way hybrid x F30), 1998 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Z70-5-2 ie Bonne Chance, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Z70-8-1, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Z74-21-5, 1991, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Z74-23-3, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Z74-26-1, Oct, 2002, Feb, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Z77-3-1, May 14, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Z77-80-1, Jan 1, 1994, July, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Z77-85-1, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Z78-99-1, July 1988, April 1989 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Z82-3-2, May 2, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Z82-49-1, Feb 6, 1997, Dec 2, 1985, July 1988, May 15, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Z83-1-1, May-June 1996, May-June 1989 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Z81-4-1, Sept 1983, May 19, 1990, July 26, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Z85-7-86-31, May 30, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Z86-30-1, April 25, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Z86-30-1, May 2, 1991, April 27, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Z86-31-8, May 30, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Z86-31-10, May 4, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Z88-22-1, May 10, 1998, August 29, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Z89-9-3, May 4, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Z90-6-1, July 17, 1996, Sept 1991 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Z90-8-2, Z91-45-5, 81-4-1, Dec 20, 1996, Aug, 1999, Dec 31, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Z90-6-1,2,4, July 17, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Z90-31-2, Oct 27, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Z91-45-5, Oct 17, 2001, Aug 10, 1999, Sept 6, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Z91-52-1, July 30, 1999, Aug 20, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Z92-8-4, May 19, 1996, April 17, 1993, Aug 26, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Z94-8-1 through 18, Feb 11, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Z94-63-10, Sept 1, 2000, May 20, 2000, October 1996 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Z76-4-1,2,3, April 9, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Z96-5-1,2, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Z97-60-Series, Aug 10, 1999, Nov 7, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Z97-64-Series, Nov 25, 2002, May 25, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Z97-66-17, May 21, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Z00-21-Series, Aug 1986, July 25, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Z00-21-Series, May 14, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Z00-36-1 and 2, March 29, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Z00-46-1, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Background Charts/Analyses, June 1, 1996, July 1986, January 30, 1994, Nov 15, 1993, Jan 13, 1994, April 13, 1990, Sept 10, 1989, 1989-1996 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Background Charts, May 10, 1995, July 1988, April 13, 1990, January 28, 1993, 1988-1995 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Lon Rombough, 1987-1988, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Lon Rombough, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Misc., n.d. (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Misc, 1966, May 1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Aleksei Gimbol, 1983-1988 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Grapes, 1950-1960 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- R.L. Forrer, 1957-1968, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- R.T. Dunstan, 1954-1971 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Grape Varieties, Developing Disease, 1973, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Life Alert, 2005-2006 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Lon Rombough, 1989-1993, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Tom DeWolf, 1998-1999, 2002, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- A Practical Ampelography, Engineers' Cross Section Book, Oct 1968, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Card File, n.d. (Box 5)